So here we go. We're going to set up rag and an knowledge base on Amazon bedrock.
Now this hands-on is a bit more complicated than the other ones.
So you've learned what you need to know from a knowledge base perspective.
This is just technical stuff if you were very curious into how things worked.
So to create a knowledge base, we need to move away from let's call the root user.
This is the root user right now. We connected to it.
We just see the account ID and we go into an IAM user.
So you type IAM in your services and then you go to the IAM console.
And you're going to go under users and you're going to create a user.
The user name is whatever you want.
I'm going to name it Stefan and I'm going to provide user access to the AWS management console.
Now I know that the recommended user type is here in Identity Center.
This is something we'll see later on right now when I make it super simple.
So I want to just create an IAM user and then you can use a custom password that you must know.
And I'm going to just enter a password that I know.
So here I go and I'm good to go.
Okay. And then we can un-take this.
I don't need to create a new password at login.
Then next click on next and we're going to attach policies directly.
And the one we're looking for is administrator access.
So we're going to give full admin power to this user.
Then we click on next and then create user and our user is successfully created.
Now we have an access to a console sign in URL with a user name and our password.
So let's go into the sign in URL right now and press enter.
And now we have this new signing page.
So the account ID will leave as is.
The user name is whatever you had before and then the password is your actual password.
And then click on sign in.
So here we go. Now I am into the console.
And I know that I am logged in using an IM user because, well, it says I am user.
It's defined and there is my account ID.
So now we're ready to go back into Amazon bedrock and then get started.
Go on the left hand side onto knowledge bases and create a knowledge base.
So the knowledge base name will just leave it as is.
The IM permissions we're going to select create and use a new service role.
So we leave the defaults.
Then we choose Amazon S3 and then we can see actually the options we have.
So we have Amazon S3, but you can also have other data sources such as a web crawler
to extract data from a web page or it could be third party data sources such as confidence
where you can store your information or a Salesforce for your own CRM or SharePoint to have
a look at your documents hosted on SharePoint.
But we'll use Amazon S3 right now and our little PDF file.
Let's click on next and next we need to create data source.
So it's going to be Amazon S3 on this account and we need to select an S3 bucket.
So now let's go into Amazon S3 and actually create an S3 bucket.
So we need to create a bucket and we need to make sure we are in U.S. East one still.
And it's a general purpose type of buckets and you just have to give it a name.
So my demo buckets knowledge base stiffen and you see this name is very long and
complicated because if you just enter a name that is already taken, for example,
test and then you click on create buckets, you're going to get an error saying,
hey, this bucket name already exists.
So the bucket name doesn't exist in my accounts, but it exists in someone else's accounts.
And so this is a problem on Amazon S3.
The bucket name needs to be unique and therefore you need to enter a unique name.
So if you copy this entire bucket name, it's not going to work because I have created this bucket myself.
So choose a name that is going to be unique to you.
Then you scroll all the way down, we don't need any of these options and we create these buckets.
So now my bucket is created and I'm going to just click on it.
And within it, this is where we can upload objects.
So let's upload a first object is going to be our evolution of the internet's
detailed and click on upload.
So it's a very simple interface to upload files onto the cloud.
And now if we look at it in our buckets, we have one object which is our PDF.
So this is great.
And now I just go into back into Amazon bedrock and we need to select an S3 URI.
So we browse Amazon S3, we refresh this, doesn't work, okay.
So let's cancel this, refresh and recreate an knowledge base.
We scroll down, click on next and then click on browse S3 and here we go.
Now we can select this Amazon S3 bucket, so we choose it and now this is filled.
So next we go, click on next, we need to select an embedding model.
So this is how to convert your data into a vector.
So different options here, but I'm just going to take the one from Amazon,
this Titan text embedding V2 and we don't touch anything on the vector dimension.
Now for the vector database, so we have several options.
If you wanted to go all the way free, then you would select PineCon.
Because PineCon, if you go on the website of PineCon, so PineCon.io.
And you go on the pricing, you see that there is a free tier, so you can start free.
And you can have up to two gigabytes of storage and then write units and
read units all the way, you're good.
So this is a setup I'm not going to do because I'm trying to demonstrate the AWS
services, of course, but if you want to stay free, I would recommend PineCon.
Now I'm going to pay some money for what I'm going to do right now.
But I'm going to do a quick create with a new vector store because this is
going to use Amazon OpenSearch Serverless, which is an AWS service,
and something they most likely want you to use.
Other services on AWS, for example, is Amazon Aura.
But so we're going to do a quick create of a new vector store.
And actually, you can see that even though they say it's cost efficient,
I really don't believe it.
So for Amazon OpenSearch Serverless pricing, it's used by computing OCU and
you have a minimum billable of two OCUs.
And OCUs are quite expensive.
So you get $0.24 per OCU per hour, which is around $172 per month.
So it's quite expensive and then you also pay for the storage.
And so what I want to share is that we are going to be conscious in this course
and make sure that we delete OpenSearch Service right after using it.
So we'll pay a minimal amount if you do the hands-on with me.
Again, good for you to know and if you follow along and you create a vector store
with me on Amazon OpenSearch Serverless, you are going to pay some money.
So please, don't forget to delete things.
Otherwise, this is going to be a very sad moment.
Okay, so let's click on create knowledge base and now we're good to go.
Again, you will get an error if you're not using an IAM user.
So this was very important to do.
So this will take a little bit of time and I'm going to pause the video until we are done.
Okay, so my knowledge base is now created.
And I can click on go to data sources to have a look at it.
So it says that yes, my data source is available.
And then what I'm going to do is click on it and then sync it to perform a synchronization
of the data that I have in my extra buckets to my database in OpenSearch.
So as you can see here, I can click on OpenSearch Service and have a look at it
and confirm that on the left hand side under dashboard,
I have access to my collection, which is my bedrock knowledge base.
So it's pretty cool.
So I want to show you a little bit how this works.
This is obviously way advanced knowledge, but I'm always curious.
So if you click on this connection collection, you can see right here that we have access
to our endpoint and we have an OpenSearch dashboard URL that we can look at to look
at what's within our collection.
And we can have a look as well as indexes to see that an index was created.
And there is one vector with six documents.
So if we go into OpenSearch dashboard and here we are, so we can visualize our data.
So to do it, we go on the left hand side under discover.
And then you have index pattern.
So we click on create index pattern.
And then we paste this name of the index in here, click on next step and then create
index pattern.
This is to, we can tell OpenSearch dashboards to look for our data.
And here we can see all the fields that were created automatically by Amazon bedrock.
So this is very handy.
Now let's go in here and go here, we click on dashboards.
We go, sorry, into discover.
And then we can have a look here into our knowledge base.
And here we have access to the actual vectors.
So this is some information around what was the text chunk of my PDF that is in here.
What is the ID?
And then what is the actual bedrock knowledge base vector?
And so all these numbers were created by the embeddings model.
So this is advanced, I know, but I want to show you the deep down things of high works.
Basically, my document was chunked and then for each chunk, a vector was created.
And so you have about one, two, three, four, five, six chunks right now for my documents.
But by the way, now I can go into Amazon bedrock and I can start testing my knowledge base.
So let's configure a model.
We're going to take, for example, again, an anthropic haiku or sonets.
Let's apply it, perfect.
And here we say who invented the world wide web click on run.
And then it's going to retrieve and share a response.
As you can see, we have pretty much the same answer as before.
And in terms of sources, we can see that now we have a link to evolution of the internet
detailed point PDF.
And if I click on it, this takes me directly into Amazon S3 into my PDF file that have uploaded.
So it's quite cool because now we have set up a full rag.
And if you want to set up properly, you would add more documents, of course, in your Amazon
S3 bucket and then you would click on the sync button.
So it's here we've practiced how to use rag.
I'm going to clean it up and to do so, I delete the knowledge base.
So click on delete and it's going to delete the knowledge base.
But this doesn't delete your open search database.
So let's wait for this to be done.
And next, this was very quick.
And next, let's go into open search service.
And under here for this collection, you're going to delete it.
Otherwise, this will incur some cost in the long run.
So that's it.
We've practiced creating an open search serverless database.
We have created a knowledge base, we've uploaded some files onto Amazon S3.
You can keep your S3 bucket running.
This is fine.
This is not going to cost you anything.
And then we were both to demonstrate how knowledge bases and rag worked.
So I'm very excited.
This was a long hands on and very advanced.
I know, but good to see.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.